<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the mayor whereas it appears by several examinations taken before me and others His Majesties justices of the peace, that there have been several endeavours and wicked contrivances influencing some apprentices and others, to enter into a detestable combination for wicked purposes against the peace and good government of this city ...</title>
            <author>City of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1680</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A33394</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C4616</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R36021</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">15586747</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 15586747</idno>
            <idno type="VID">103992</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A33394)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 103992)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1589:3)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the mayor whereas it appears by several examinations taken before me and others His Majesties justices of the peace, that there have been several endeavours and wicked contrivances influencing some apprentices and others, to enter into a detestable combination for wicked purposes against the peace and good government of this city ...</title>
                  <author>City of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
                  <author>Clayton, Robert, Sir, 1629-1707.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 broadside.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Samuel Roycroft ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1680]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title from first 4 lines of text.</note>
                  <note>Date of publication suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Broadside cut into 2 leaves.</note>
                  <note>"Given at Guild-Hall London, the 30th. day of March, anno Dom. 1680. And in the xxij. year of the reign of our Sovereign Lord Charles the Second, by the grace of God, of England, Scotland, France and Ireland, King, defender of the faith, &amp;c."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>London (England) --  History --  17th century.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  London.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-07</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:103992:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>blazon of the City of London, consisting of a shield bearing the cross of St. George (patron saint of England) with a sword (emblem of the martyrdom of St. Paul, patron saint of London) in the first quarter of the shield</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>By the Mayor.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas it appears by ſeveral Examinations taken before Me and others his Majeſties Iuſtices of the Peace, that there have been ſeveral Endeavours and wicked Contrivances influencing ſome Apprentices and others, to enter into a deteſtable Combination for wicked Purpoſes againſt the Peace and good Government of this City; ſeveral of the Complices being now in Cuſtody to anſwer the Law.</p>
            <p>And foreſeeing the Dangerous and ſad Conſequences (both as to our Religion and Peace) in the Circumſtances we are now in, that Riotous and Seditious Aſſemblies may run into, by the Managery and Artifices of deſigning Papiſts and other Perſons diſaffected to the Government: And the great Numbers of unaccomptable Perſons that fill the Suburbs of this City, many of whom are of Deſperate Fortunes, and of worſe Principles, who may take Advantages to improve Riots and unlawful Aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>blies, to worſe Purpoſes than Apprentices might intend them.</p>
            <p>For Avoiding and Preventing any ſuch wicked Deſigns and Evils that might thereupon enſue, and for preventing the Miſchiefs that Apprentices and others might unwarily run into, and for the preſervation of the Peace, Honour, and good Government of this City.</p>
            <p>Theſe are (by the Advice of my Brethren the Aldermen) in his Majeſties Name, ſtreightly to Command and require all Maſters of Families, that they take great heed and care to keep their Apprentices and Servants ſtrictly under their Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands; And that they Warn and Admoniſh them againſt all ſuch Combinations and Riotous Aſſemblies and Proceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings, Eſpecially on the Lords day and Feſtivals; that by their due care in keeping them to their reſpective Duties, all un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>due and unlawfull Aſſemblies may be prevented, which in all times have been of Miſcheivous Conſequences, and greatly to the diſhonour of God, the Scandal of the Proteſtant Religion, and the good government of this City.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:103992:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>Theſe are alſo to Charge and Command all Conſtables and Beadles to take care that the Civil Watches be duly kept, and in full Proportions according to the Law in that caſe, and upon any defect to Repreſent it to Me, that effectual care may be taken for the Redreſſing any neglect or abuſes therein; And I do further Recommend it to the Care of the Alder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, Deputy, and Common Council-men of each Ward, that they ſometimes, with ſome other Citizens of the Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bourhood, when they ſhall think fit, do walk the Rounds, and ſee that the Watches be duly kept, and do their reſpective Duties. And it is alſo recommended to their Care, that this may be ſpeedily Communicated to all Inhabitants within their reſpective Wards.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Given at <hi>Guild-Hall</hi> London, <date>the 30<hi>th.</hi> day of <hi>March, Anno Dom.</hi> 1680. And in the xxxij. year of the Reign of our Sovereign Lord <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, by the Grace of God, of <hi>England, Scotland, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> King, Defender of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
               <lb/> God ſave the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed by <hi>Samuel Roycroft,</hi> Printer to the Honourable City of <hi>LONDON.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
